Guide to the United Food and Commercial Workers International Union Local 325, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records 1931-1997 AIS.1997.15
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United Food and Commercial Workers International Union Local 325, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records
1931-1997
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United Food and Commercial Workers International Union. Local 325 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.1997.15
5 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
The United Foods and Commercial Workers International Union Local 325, formerly known as Canning and Pickle Workers Union Local 325, was founded in 1937 to represent employees of the H.J. Heinz Company, chiefly employed at the North Side plant in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. The records include contract books from 1941-1994, union constitutions and by-laws, a job description book, union newsletters, photographs, and oral histories. Also included are various publications of the H.J. Heinz Company written for their employees.
History
On May 17, 1937, the Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America (AFL) issued a charter to Canning and Pickle Workers Union Local 325, where a union organizing committee had recently been formed. Also in May 1937, the Union was victorious in an election conducted by the National Labor Relations Board, but the H.J. Heinz Company refused to sign a written contract, and from August 15, 1937 to January 6, 1941, employees of the company worked without one. Following a protracted long legal battle, the company was ordered by the United States Supreme Court to sign an agreement with the Union reached through collective bargaining. The Supreme Court ruling established a paramount precedence for all collective bargaining agreements in the United States. In an immediate upshot locally, Westinghouse Electric Corporation was similarly obligated to sign an agreement with the United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America Local 601. A merger of unions in 1979 created the United Food and Commercial Workers and the name of the local was changed accordingly.
Scope and Content Notes
These papers include contract books, union constitutions and by-laws, a job description book and other documents relating to working conditions and union activities, and the newsletters of united Food and Commercial Workers International Union, Local 325. Also included are background material, photographs, and oral histories. Some materials are photocopies of material in possession of the union.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged as follows:
Series I. Historical Material, 1930s-1940s
Series II. Contracts, Job Descriptions, and Employee Documents, 1941-1996
Series III. Oral Histories, 1997
Series IV. Oral History Transcripts
Series V. H.J. Heinz Company Publications, 1961-1996
Series VI. Union Newsletters, 1944-1996
Series VII. Oversize Materials
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Robert E. Timmons, Jr., President/Business Agent, UFCW 325 in 1997
Previous Citation
United Food and Commercial Workers International Union Local 325, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records, 1931-1997, AIS.1997.15, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Records of United Food and Commercial Workers International Union, Local 325 (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1931-1997, ue199715, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Existence and Location of Originals
The original documents of photocopied materials which do not have corresponding original documents within the collection are in the possession of UFCW Local 325 (Pittsburgh, Pa.).
Related Material
http://www.library.pitt.edu/labor_legacy
Separated Material
The nine cassettes containing oral history interviews from this collection can be found in cassette cabinet 3, drawer 4, at the Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh.
Newsletters; Constitutions; Collective labor agreements; Annual reports; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Oral histories (Document genres); Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Food industry and trade -- Employees -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Collective labor agreements -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Labor; Bylaws (Administrative records); Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America; Canning and Pickle Workers Union. Local 325 (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Cypher, Frances; H.J. Heinz Company; Heidenreich, Charles; Koontz, John; United Food and Commercial Workers International Union. Local 325 (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Vinski, David; Ware, Elizabeth
- Historical Material, 1930s-1940s; I.
  - H.J. Heinz Company History, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Related to 1937 Strike (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - National War Labor Board Night Ruling, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - National War Labor Board Ruling, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 30th Anniversary Banquet Program, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Contracts, Job Descriptions, and Employee Documents, 1941-1996; II.
  - Contracts, 1941-1955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Contracts, 1949-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Contracts, 1971-1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Constitutions and By-Laws, 1951-1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America Constitutions, 1956-1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Contracts of Other Unions, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Union Manuals, Job Evaluation and Negotiation Workshop, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Union Seniority and Payroll, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - New Employee Orientation, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Job Descriptions Book Index, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Job Grade 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Job Grade 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Job Grade 3-4, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Job Grade 5, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Job Grade 6, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Job Grade 7, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Job Grade 8, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Job Grade 9, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Job Grade 10, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Job Grade 11, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Job Grade 12-13, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Job Grade 14, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Job Grade 15, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - H.J. Heinz Company Employee Benefits Booklets, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Local 325 Job Descriptions, undated (Box 2, Volume 1)
  - Removed Items, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Oral Histories, 1997; III.
  - Cypher, Frances, August 20, 1997 (Box 3, Cassette 1-2)
  - Heidenreich, Charles, July 16, 1997 (Box 3, Cassette 3)
  - Heidenreich, Charles, September 3, 1997 (Box 3, Cassette 4)
  - Koontz, John, May 12, 1997 (Box 3, Cassette 5)
  - Koontz, John, June 18, 1997 (Box 3, Cassette 6)
  - Vinski, David, September 3, 1997 (Box 3, Cassette 7)
  - Ware, Elizabeth, July 16, 1997 (Box 3, Cassette 8)
  - Warwick, John, July 16, 1997 (Box 3, Cassette 9)
- Oral History Transcript, IV.
  - Frances Cypher Oral History Interview Transcript, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Charles Heidenreich Oral History Interview Transcript, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - John Koontz Oral History Interview Transcripts, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - David Vinski Oral History Interview Transcript, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Elizabeth Ware Oral History Interview Transcript, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - John Warwick Oral History Interview Transcript, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- H.J. Heinz Company Publications, 1961-1966; V.
  - H.J. Heinz Company Annual Report, 1977-1995 (Box 4, Folder 7-21)
  - 57 News, 1961-1970 (Box 4, Folder 22-29)
  - Heinz Line, 1982-1989 (Box 4, Folder 30-33)
  - Heinz Quarterly, 1984-1996 (Box 4, Folder 34-39)
  - Heinz Report to Employees, 1984-1994 (Box 4, Folder 40-43)
  - Heinz VIP News, 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - News Beat for Active and Retired Employees of Heinz USA, 1972-1980 (Box 4, Folder 45-47)
  - Pittsburgh Factory News, 1982-1988 (Box 4, Folder 48-49)
  - Processed Food News- for Heinz USA Processed Foods Division Employees, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 50-51)
- Newsletters and News, 1944-1996; VI.
  - Union Newsletters, 1944-1996; V.
    Scope and Contents note
    This series contains most, but not all, issues of the Union's newsletter, 325 News. It was published monthly, later bimonthly, starting in 1944. The newsletters are arranged chronologically, one year's issues per folder. Issues for 1956 and 1958 are lacking.
  - Copies of 325 News, 1944-1996 (Box 5, Folder 01-40)
  - Originals of 325 News, 1944-1996 (Box 6, Folder 01-40)
- Oversize Materials, VII.
  Scope and Content Notes
  these materials were added to the finding aid in January 2011.
  - Local 325 Picket Sign for Strike against H.J. Heinz Co., 1. (Map-case 3, Drawer 14)
  - Local 325 Photograph, 2.